Guide to the Asian Maps Collection, 1771-1945 RL.11713
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Asian maps collection
1771-1945
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11713
4.0 Linear Feet 10 items
The Asian Maps Collection comprises maps of Korea, China, and Japan, dated from 1771-1945. Several of the maps are full color, and include woodblock prints.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Asian Maps Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2018 and 2020.
Collection Overview
The Asian Maps Collection comprises maps of Korea, China, and Japan, dated from 1771-1945. Several of the maps are full color, and include woodblock prints. Several maps include information on military installments. A few maps include hand-written notations.
Korea (North) -- Maps; China -- Maps; Japan -- Maps; Maps (documents); Maps
- Map and guide of Pyongyang, Korea, 1921-1930; 39 x 53 cm (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Age end of Taisho era to beginning of Showa era.
- Map of China incident, Shanghai, Jinan, 1936; 52 x 37 cm (Box 1)
  Shows Shanghai city, Truce zone of Shanghai Incident, Japanese resident area, Tsingtao city map, Jinan city map. Published by the Oriental Culture Association.
- Newest China Incident Map, 1937; 54 x 73 cm (Box 1)
  Shows air bases throughout the region. Publisher Shogakukan.
- Kyoto Saibun Meisho, 1887; 48 x 72 cm (Box 1)
  Original Japanese woodblock print Map of Kyoto, with 45 decorative vignettes, dated Meiji 20. Original cover boards and title slip.
- Dainihon Do-Chu-Ko-Tei Taizen, 1771; 700 x 17 cm (Box 2)
  Japanese woodblock map of Japan.
- Map of Japan, Meiji 10, 1877; 37 x 144 cm (Box 2)
  Original Japanese woodblock print, fine impressions and colors, some repairs. Original cover boards and title slip.
- 大東亞戦 戦争局圖 (Dai Tōa-sen sensō kyokuzu), 1942 (Box 1)
  Publisher: 東洋文化協會 (Tōyō bunka kyōkai); Other names associated: "画報躍進之日本" ("Gahō yakushin no Nihon") - parent publication; Description: Came with vol. 7 issue 5 of 画報躍進之日本 ("Gahō yakushin no Nihon"" (serial title). Colorful map spanning Japan to India, including Australia. Countries are labelled and decorated with cultural images. UK & US boats are marked in the ocean (some sinking); many locations have Japanese flags, or bombs with Japanese flags pointed at them.; Dimensions: 36.3 x 24.3 cm.
- 支那の現状と資源分布圖: 十一月中旬調 (Shina no genjō to shigen bunpuzu: Jū-ichi-gatsu chūjun shirabe), 1938 (Box 1)
  Publisher: 東洋協会調査部 (Tōyō kyōkai chōsa-bu); Other names associated: President of 森下仁丹株式会社 (Morishita Jintan Kabushiki Kaisha), 森下博 (Morishita Hiroshi) - message on top-left of map; Description: Map of China with natural resources, current military locations, etc. Notes locations of Japanese, Communist and Islamic (回教) forces. Includes notes on the map as well as list of members of the Tōyō kyōkai & their work.; Dimensions: 54 x 77.5 cm.
- 支那事変要圖 (Shina jihen yōzu), 1945 (Box 1)
  Publisher: 文藝春秋 (Bungei shunjū); Other names associated:; Description: Came with vol. 25 issue 11 of 文藝春秋 (Bungei shunjū) (serial title). Black and white map of China with inset zoom of Shanghai city. Includes 中國軍隊一覧表(Chūgoku guntai ichiran-hyō) breaking down Chinese government and miliary branches with names of individuals. This copy has hand-added red marks on some locations without explanation, does not obscure text.; Dimensions: 53 x 79 cm.
- 東京區分繪圖 (Tōkyō kubun ezu), 1878 (Box 1)
  Publisher: 濱山堂 (Hamayamadō); Other names associated: Revisions/editing by 石井秀胤 (Ishii Hidetane); personal name associated with the publication: 丸山正助 (Maruyama Shōsuke); Description: Printed map of Tokyo's wards, marked in color. Chart in lower-left lists further neighborhood divisions and addresses of ward offices. Includes original slipcover, with what appears to be handwritten text on reverse. Slipcover indicated this is 銅版 (dōhan), and its original price was 25 sen.; Dimensions: 70 x 50 cm.